Joseph Forman

Highly Skilled well-rounded Professional

Centerton, AR 72719 josephforman@ymail.com 479-696-1558

A highly skilled and professional bi-lingual manager / supervisor with 10+ years of diverse experience in fast paced industrial, production, government and customer service fields. Knowledgeable in industrial manufacturing and production, electrical, electronic, mechanical, hydraulic, and pneumatic maintenance, welding/fabrication, and repair of machinery and equipment. Seeking a position of responsibility as a professional to utilize my skills and proficiency in a renowned organization.

Professional strengths:

- Ability to devise innovative solutions in a fast-paced environment
- Excellent verbal and written communication skills
- Skilled in electrical, mechanical, hydraulic and pneumatic maintenance
- Skilled in metal welding and fabrication of parts and structure.
- Skilled in operation, maintenance and repair of small and heavy equipment.
- Result-oriented, highly motivated and ability to meet deadlines
- Ability to pass physical examination and meet legal and moral standards
- In-depth knowledge of logistical handling, transport and storing materiel
- Possess knowledge and experience of advanced leadership skills.
- Ability to repair/operate computer hardwar and software operating systems i.e.Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint and internet
- Familiar with the ins and outs of supply chain management (i.e. storage and delivery, procurement, warehouse management and record keeping)
- Possess excellent planning and organizational skills
- Ability to manage/supervise several teams/departments

Work Experience

Shop Manager/Lead Mechanic

E3 - Bentonville, AR February 2017 to Present

Schedule and administer fleet maintenance program.

Communicates availability of vehicles for service with operations department, maintenance manager and/or other personnel as required

Diagnose & repair all truck related equipment.

Supervise maintenance operations. Plan and distribute the workload. Delegate responsibilities as appropriate and monitor performances. While involved in reviewing personnel actions (discipline, promotions) all such actions are further reviewed and approved by higher management Ensure compliance on a day to day basis with State, Federal and Company requirements Work closely with location manager providing status of maintenance and budget performance/ requirements. Open/review/close repair orders

Order parts, lubes, fuel and subcontract repair work

Supervise fueling & cleaning as required. Arrange services for building and ground keeping as required

Identiy and recommend actions to improve operating efficiency

Complete special projects as assigned. Required to perform hands on work activities

Provide leadership to ensure compliance with company safety policy

Carry out all other duties as may be requested by line manager

Pass on work orders from supervisors to shift mechanics and accountable for reporting the quality of the work performed

Conduct safety observations as directed, coach where appropriate, and forward to maintenance manager

Perform normal duties as a Mechanic

Conduct quality work inspections of work performed by shift mechanics

Train mechanics to fully develop all skill sets.

Willingness to work any shift.

Mechanical Assembly Technician

Delta Systems & Automation, Inc. - Rogers, AR November 2015 to August 2016

Reading and interpret ingassembly blueprints or specifications manuals and plan assembly or building operations.

Inspecting operating, and testing completed products to verify functioning, machine capabilities, or conformance to customer specifications.

Positioning or aligning components for assembly, manually or using hoists or lifts

Verification of conformance of parts using measuring instruments, such as calipers, gauges, or micrometers.

Lay out and drill, ream, tap, or cut parts for assembly.

Assemble drive systems by aligning and meshing gears in gearboxes.

Set up and operation of metalworking machines, such as milling or grinding machines and metal forming machine likes brakes or shears.

Maintenance Supervisor/Inventory Manager/General Manager/Demolitions Supervisor/HR Manager/Facility Operations Manager

SA Concepts - Springdale, AR March 2012 to August 2015

March 2012-August 2015

Maintenance Supervisor/Inventory Manager/General Manager/Demolitions Supervisor/HR Manager/Facility Operations Manager

- •Diagnosed malfunctions in machine and equipment.
- •Directed and assisted in dismantling, welding, assembling and installing inustrial machinery during plan repair, modification and expansion.
- •Interpreted company policies to employees.
- •Implemented and enforced safety regulations.
- Suggested changes in working conditions/environment, and use of equipment to increase efficiency of the facility.

- •Conducted training and safety for facility employees on specific equipment.
- Proficient skills to evaluate, resolve, repair, and construct and/or modify equipment.
- Ability to interpret specifications, and job orders to employees and customers.
- Establish and/or adjusted work procedures to meet project and production schedules.
- Recommended measures to improve production methods, equipment performance and quality of product.
- •Maintained proper communication with leads and supervisors to coordinate activities of individual departments relative to production, maintenance and construction projects.
- Planed, budgeted and schedule facility operations and modifications including cost estimates, bid sheets, layouts and contract for construction and acquisitions.

Automated Logistic Specialist/Diesel Mechanic/Heavy Equipment Operator-Transportation and Logistics

United States Army - McChord AFB, WA February 2007 to September 2010

Washington

February 2007 till September 2010

Automated Logistic Specialist/Diesel Mechanic/Heavy Equipment Operator-Transportation and Logistics

- Established and maintained records like stock lists, materiel control, inventory, supply reports and accounting
- Reviewed and verified quantities received against bills of contracts, lading, shipping documents and purchase requests
- Responsible for unloading and storing incoming equipments and supplies
- Administered document control procedures and maintained stock locator system
- Handled the tasks of processing requests and turn-in documents at direct support level through warehousing section
- Performed prescribed load list and shop stock list duties according to manual and automated supply applications
- Handled the tasks of preparing, explaining and distributing shipping documents
- Responsible for operating material-handling equipment
- Handled the tasks of providing logistical support to ensure that equipments was ready for use
- Operated and maintained SAMS-1E system with all updates and upgrades
- Handled the tasks of managing and maintaining personnel files
- Responsible for compiling and tracking man-hours accounting for each shop
- Updated the maintenance officer about daily work activities
- Handled the tasks of managing a shop stock of more than 200 items that cost in excess of \$1,000,000
- Responsible for maintaining automated and manual accounting records like turn-ins and posts receipts
- Handled the tasks of unloading and inspecting incoming equipments and supplies

- Assisted in military recruitment and managed low rank soldiers' supply chain procedures and methods
- Maintained and organized supply room and warehouse
- Diagnosing and repair of diesel vehicles.

Floor Manager

McDonald's

July 2003 to January 2006

Conducted daily closing procedures

- Managed staff and hours
- Proper accountability of finances and personnel

Professional Achievements:

- Maintained and improved percentage of reconciliation by 97%
- Scored outstanding ratings in all command inspections

Education

High School Diploma

Monache High School - Porterville, CA 1999

Skills

Troubleshooting (10+ years), Mechanical (10+ years), Welding (4 years), Electrical (3 years), Training & Development (6 years), Inventory Management (7 years), Management (10+ years), Supply Chain Management (7 years), Microsoft Office (9 years), Production Management (3 years), Maintenance (7 years)

Military Service

Branch: army

Service Country: United States

Rank: E-4

February 2007 to September 2010

Logistics and diesel mechanic

Commendations: Too many to list.

Certifications/Licenses

Forklift Certified